# Reito Serizawa

Jersey City, NJ | (979) 661-4280 | reitoserizawa@gmail.com | Portfolio | GitHub | LinkedIn

## **Software Engineer**

Bilingual software engineer, experienced in full-stack web development, object-oriented programming, and test-driven development. Superb problem-solving and data management skills sharpened by analyzing data sets and tackling application issues. Exceptional collaborative skills honed in the software development life cycle. Possesses a passion for continuous self-improvement.

#### **Technical Skills**

JavaScript, Python, Ruby, React, Redux, Ruby on Rails, Django, SQL, PostgreSQL, Git, Heroku, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, REST APIs

## **Technical Projects**

### Portfolio - GitHub (Frontend) | GitHub (Backend) | Live

- Built the full-stack portfolio website with JavaScript, Python, React, Django, HTML, and CSS, deployed on GitHub Pages.
- Followed the software development life cycle by analyzing the requirements and maintaining based on feedback.
- Created a RESTful API utilizing a relational database management system to bring flexibility and accessibility to the data.

# StudyBuddy - GitHub | Demo

A chat application to create a profile and a chat room to study programming with others, and send and delete messages.

- Built the full-stack application with Python and Django following the MVT architecture.
- Created a custom user model for the Django authentication system to customize user profile information.
- Designed a REST API with CRUD operations to connect with the client side by Django REST framework.

#### Zoomies - GitHub | Demo

A dog park application to create a profile of pet dogs, check in and out at dog parks, and see active dogs at each park with profiles.

- Built the full-stack application with JavaScript, Ruby, React, and Ruby on Rails following the MVC pattern.
- Implemented features to check in and out, and view active dogs at each park by managing relational databases.
- Handled unauthorized access protection and auto-login persistence by using bcrypt's hashing and salting, and sessions.

## Tippie - GitHub | Demo

A reviewing application for restaurants and servers that allows users to tip based on the service provided by each server.

- Built the full-stack application with a REST API to improve data handling by converting Yelp API through REST Client.
- Integrated ActiveRecord validations in Ruby on Rails to monitor reviews to avoid online insults.
- Leveraged the knowledge with serializers and connected each relational database to access and use data from the front end.

## Work Experience

# **Blued Japan**

Marketing Business Development Manager

Tokyo, Japan May 2020-October 2021

- Initiated business development and marketing activities by leading software development and marketing teams.
- Built relationships with 6 nonprofit organizations (NPO), 3 corporations, and 500+ lesbian, gay, bisexual, and transgender (LGBT) related facilities, and executed collaborations through educational activities, co-produced products, and events.
- Managed 10+ offline advertising plans and 2 signboard plans in Japan returning an average conversion rate of 3%.

# eBay

Tokyo, Japan

Associate Sales Manager, Direct Sales, Business Development

June 2019-May 2020

- Generated sales leads and acquired large merchants for cross-border trade opportunities through meetings and calls.
- Assessed the clients' needs and advised selling and marketing plans by installing software tools to reduce workforce and cost.
- Developed partnerships with e-commerce software vendors and collaborated with their services to improve client revenue.

#### **AlphaSights**

Associate, Strategic Consulting Division

Tokyo, Japan; Central, Hong Kong March 2018-April 2019

- Managed client relationships through regular communication and successfully grew accounts by client recommendations.
- Led 35+ global projects across Consumer Goods (30%), Healthcare (20%), and Financial Services (16%).
- Contributed to the generation of an average \(\frac{1}{2}\),000,000/month in profits, on average, on projects across global markets.

#### **Education**

#### **Flatiron School**

Full-stack Software Engineering Bootcamp

New York, USA April 2022-July 2022

# **Senshu University**

Bachelor of Arts (B.A) in English Literature

Kanagawa, Japan April 2014-March 2018

## **University of Oregon**

Oregon, USA June 2016-March 2017

Exchange program in English and Entrepreneurship